SERGIO ALEJANDRO VALBUENA MATEUS

707 Mulberry Ln, Davis, CA, 95616 | +01 (707)-567-9287 | savalbuena@ucdavis.edu

Objective

To continue my professional and academic development within the water resources field of civil engineering and to utilize my analytical, teamwork, and visionary skills to contribute to the quality of water resources research. Interested in the understanding of Lake Hydrodynamics coupling numerical simulations and experimental fieldwork with special focus on the littoral zone, and lake management strategies.

Skills

- Fluent in English and Spanish. TOEFL IBT:91
- Excellent communicative and analytical skills, working diligently with others.
- Process and apply new skills and concepts quickly.
- Highly motivated to achieve goals with strong leadership qualities.
- Time series analysis, and data management
- Literate with Microsoft Office, AutoCAD, OpenFOAM®.
- Basic knowledge in Project Management and water resources systems.
- Primary knowledge in ArcGIS, FLOW3D, HEC-RAS.

Education

Ph.D. Water Resources, minor in applied mathematics

University of California – Davis, USA Fall 2018 – Present

Master of Science M.Sc., Civil and Environmental Engineering

University of California – Davis, USA Fall-2017 – Present

Bachelor of Science, Civil Engineering

Colombian University of Engineering Julio Garavito — Bogotá, Colombia Valedictorian GPA: Colombia System 4.3/5.0 – USA System 3.75/4.0

Fall-2011 - Fall 2016

SERGIO ALEJANDRO VALBUENA MATEUS

707 Mulberry Ln, Davis, CA, 95616 | +01 (707)-567-9287 | savalbuena@ucdavis.edu

Work Experience

GSR and TA positions, UC Davis

Jan-2018 - Present

- Teaching assistant for hydraulics classes and GSR for Fabián A. Bombardelli
- ❖ Lake Tahoe Nearshore network management.

Civil Engineer

Sept 2016 - Sep 2017

Engineer Alejandro Duran

- * Hydrologic and Hydraulic analysis for wetlands located in Cundinamarca, Colombia.
- Highway hydraulic design

Project Engineer

Jan 2016-Sep 2016

INNOVATECH STRATEGIC SOLUTIONS S.A.S — Based in Houston, Texas, USA, Office in Bogotá, Colombia.

- Pavement designs and subgrade stabilization.
- Project manager for gravity wall constructed for Gran Tierra Energy Inc.;
- Engineering analysis and developed design for flooding problem in Alberdi, Paraguay.